Hello and welcome. In this video, we
explore
Shopify connector enhancements in
product information area. And we will
start by looking at the item list and
scroll down to the very special item,
which I'm going to
add to Shopify.
Do you want to explore the my Shopify?
Of course we do. Exactly the purpose.
And this is the item
with image,
which looks by the way differently.
Uh description, price, and
color and material description is
something new. Can I choose one? The
different one? Let's pick gray.
Color has changed. Green.
Exactly.
Brown.
Aha.
Now I finally see the image which we
used for item itself.
But it says that fabric, the material,
is not available. Probably the brown one
is the using the color.
Interesting. How did we do that? Let's
go back to Business Central.
This is our item with the image which we
exported, but if you go to the related
item variants, you can see that this
item has four variants.
And each variant has image. So, yeah,
this image is now exported to Shopify as
well. But moreover, it also has item
attributes. We can see that color is
beige and material description is
fabric. There are other attributes,
but they are up or uh
noticeably not involved into in in the
export.
They only added as a description.
But these ones are used. How's that?
If we will search for item attributes,
the setup page,
you can see the new column. It's only
visible if you have Shopify uh connector
installed with uh
uh some stores connected.
You need to enable connector. Then you
can see different options. And you can
see that you can export some of the
attributes as option in the Shopify.
So apparently this specific item or
variant has two of these attributes
defined and now when they export them as
a product in in in Shopify, they are
also used
to define the items.
All right, that's interesting. But here
is more. If you go back to the online
store, we can see the idea that there
are something
with the catalogs.
And we have a collection.
For example, we have comfort sitting
collection where we gathered all chairs.
What about dining table collection?
Nothing.
So our chairs were added automatically
to the collection. That's another
feature which we would like to explore.
Let's go back to Business Central. From
the item list, we will navigate to
Shopify
shop card and explore it from there.
Shopify shops.
My Shopify card and here we got an extra
setting.
Custom product collections.
As you already know in many other
places, you can start by importing
collections from the Shopify and then
you can decide which collection you want
to assign to items as soon as they
exported to Shopify from Business
Central.
You can select many but probably you
want a little bit more
specific. For example, sitting
collection, I'm only added if item is in
category chair.
And the table collection is for items in
the category, you guess, table.
That particular can be useful in a case
when you need to perform something which
is called tax override. Yeah, sometimes
some items use not normal tax rate but
the reduced one. And to help Shopify to
understand that, they you can add item
to specific collection, which is
configured as a tax override. You can
always learn more in the documentation.
It's very con- convenient feature.
All right.
Let's go to the list of products.
Where we have our Tokyo chair
with different options, and let's try to
add another item.
Now, I'm adding a fan desk. It's item
without variants.
Let's see how it was added to the
Shopify. And we will start by exploring
what dining table collection. So, table
is there.
We can open the cart. We can see that
variants. Yes, because
uh this table also have a option
color and uh and sitting capacity. But,
it's only selection of one. Why? Again,
because this table this item in Business
Central has no variants.
But, what we have? We have a different
items. Let's add them as variants.
So, what's happening? Sometimes,
even if in e-commerce portal Shopify,
you prefer to have a list to be items
with variants and options, in the
Business Central, you may decide to have
a flat list when each variant is
actually individual item.
Fair enough, there are some reasons to
do that. One of them it's
maybe using assembly bill of material,
which can be only connected to the
parent item, and not to variant.
There are also couple of more fields in
the in the item item list, which is not
available to variants.
So, we can we can utilize function which
is called add item as a Shopify variant,
and add couple of more items.
Same table but different sitting
capacity. Let's click okay.
And they were added.
Back to Shopify.
So, the same item, same column, but now
we can see more seats. And if I select
different seats, you can notice that
price is changing as well. So,
apparently the number of seats and
number and price is very much related.
Yes, because we defined price per
different item as well.
All right.
What about if you want to actually
import items from Shopify to Business
Central? That's a different scenario,
but again, it's super flexible, depends
on your
situation and the setup and the moment
in the implementation, you can use one
or another approach. So, let's switch
back to Business Central.
In the Business Central Shopify shop
card, and we decided to synchronize from
Shopify and allow creation of the items.
Let's go to the list of products and
choose synchronization sync products.
And the next action we will do we
synchronize
product images.
And now in the created item,
which was created based on information
from Shopify, you can see image that's
expected.
Uh cost information, price price
information, all expected, but something
new. Now we got the marketing text as
well. Because we have a toggle about
marketing text, now you can get it from
Shopify as well. So, if you launch uh
start with Business Central and connect
it to Shopify, you which which you
already have a rich product information,
you can always start by uploading
catalog from
from Shopify.
All right, that was a quick walk through
through the enhancement in product
information management area in the
Shopify connector.
Uh
let's stay in touch. Please reach out to
us via LinkedIn and Viva Engage. You can
also find more videos in the on our
YouTube channel.
Thank you.